Okay.
So we're going to set up the wi fi programming section by adding a few new files.
So first, let's add a new source file.
So let's add a new source file in the main here.
And call it wi fi app dot c.
And now let's add a new header file.
And call it wi fi app h.
And let's add another header file.
And call it tasks common.
And in this set of file, we'll keep all the information for the free autos tasks that will create throughout
the course.
And now let's head over to the C make list file and now we're going to add the wi fi app source file.
Okay.
Great.
And now let's head over to the wife of a --, and he will define the wifely application settings
and create the network interface objects for the access point.
And the station also will add some preliminary message IDs for the application tasks and a structure
for the message queue.
Additionally, we'll have a prototype for a function to send a message to the cube and another for starting
the wi fi application task.
So first we need to include.
ESPN network interface, and that's necessary for the network interface objects.
So here, let's define the Wi-Fi application settings.
And let's first define the wi fi app as a side.
And we'll call it SB 32 AP.
And that's the access point.
Name.
And in case you need a little clarification, the SSA D is the service set identifier and you'll encounter
this when trying to connect to a wireless network.
So when we connect later, you'll see the ISP 32 SSI ID to show up in the list of wireless networks
on your PC or mobile device.
Okay.
So next, let's define the wi fi AP password.
And this is the password that you'll into when connecting to the ESP via the Asus I.D. we had just defined
the now call it password for simplicity, but you can call it whatever you like.
So this will be the Wi-Fi access point password.
Okay.
So now let's define the Wi-Fi app channel.
And we'll use Channel one as the Access Point Channel.
And regarding Wi-Fi channels, the ISP 32 operates in the 2.4 gigahertz range, where there are 14 channels
spaced five megahertz apart, except for a 12 megahertz base before Channel 14.
So to guarantee no interference in any circumstances.
The Wi-Fi protocol requires 16.25 to 22 megahertz of channel separation, as shown here.
And if you check the impressive documentation and the resources that I've provided, it's mentioned
that there are some factors that should be considered by the developer when programming channel selection
behavior, which are interference concerns, legal considerations and FCC rules and transmit power.
For example, one eight or 2.11 transmitter is using Channel one.
The other may use Channel five or six, and using Channel two or three is not recommended in about legal
considerations.
Channels one through 11 may be used safely in most countries in the world.
So we went with Channel one in this course.
But feel free to check out this document or any other resources for additional information if you have
concerns about channel selection.
So next, we'll define the wi fi app visibility, which we'll call wi fi app assisted hidden.
And this will be zero.
And this defines the Wi-Fi access point.
Visibility of the ISP 32 and zero makes it visible, which means that you will actually see the ISP
32 SSD in your list of networks when trying to connect to it.
All right.
So let's comment.
App visibility.
Okay.
So next, let's define the FI app.
Max connection's.
And I'll into five here.
But you can make it whatever you like.
For example, you may only want to allow one device to connect.
All right, so this is our app, max clients.
The next will define the wi fi app beacon interval.
As 100 milliseconds.
And the beacon broadcasts interval is the time lag between each of the beacons sent by your router or
access point.
In the case it's the ESB 32.
So by definition, the lower the value, the smaller the time lag, which means that the beacon is sent
more frequently in, the higher the value, the bigger the time lag, which means that the beacon is
sent less frequently.
So the beacon is needed for your devices to receive information about the particular router.
When our case, the ISP in the beacon includes some information such as the side timestamp and other
various parameters, and most of the routers out of the box has a default beacon interval function value
set at 100 milliseconds, and the implications of the high beacon interval may be that you'll achieve
better throughput and thus better speed and performance.
And a lower beacon interval allows for faster discovery of the routers because it sends beacons more
frequently.
And this can help with catching the beacon in poor reception environments.
And if we check the impressive documentation, the beacon intervals available range from 100 to 60000
milliseconds with the default being 100 milliseconds.
So we'll go with 100 milliseconds in this course.
Okay.
So let's comment.
AP Beacon interval.
As 100 milliseconds.
As recommended.
Or default.
Okay.
So now let's define.
The wi fi access point IP address.
As 192.168.0.1
and this will be our default IP.
And again, this is the IP that we assigned to the soft tape and we are statically configuring the interface
of the ISP 32.
So next, let's define the Wi-Fi app, Gateway.
Which is also 192.168.0.1.
And that's our AP default.
Gateway.
Which should be the same as the IP address.
Okay.
So next, let's define.
The wi fi app net mask.
As to 55.255.255.0.
And that's a peanut mask.
So next, let's define.
The wi fi app bandwidth.
And we can use the wi fi underscore BW underscore HD 20, and that's from the wi fi driver for a 20
megahertz bandwidth.
And 40 megahertz is also an option.
And if you check the impressive documentation, the default bandwidth for station and AP mode is HD
40.
And in AP mode, the actual bandwidth is negotiated between the AP and the stations that connect to
the AP and it is HD 40.
If the AP in one of the stations supports HD 40, otherwise it's HD 20.
And there are various options for stations slash AP mode.
So feel free to read up on that.
And I'll just summarize the last paragraph here that theoretically the HD 40 can gain better throughput
because the maximum data rate can be up to 150 megabits per second or 72 megabits per second for HD
20.
So just summarizing and based on what I've read through, out of the resources, 20 megahertz minimizes
channel interference but is not suitable for applications with high data rates.
So feel free to choose the bandwidth that best suits your application while considering the surrounding
environment.
But I would go with 20 megahertz, so our AP bandwidth will be 20 megahertz.
And 40 megahertz is the other option.
Okay.
So next let's define the WI by state power save.
And from the driver, we'll use wi fi power.
Save none.
And again, let's go to the documentation and I'll just highlight that when we call S.P. Wife, I said
power save.
With wi fi power saved, none will disable modem sleep entirely and this has much higher power consumption
but provides minimum latency for receiving wi fi data in real time.
In the default mode, modem sleep mode is wi fi power save minimum modem, but will use flight five
power save none.
Okay.
So Power Save is not used.
So next, let's provide a definition.
For the maximum assisted length.
And that length is 32.
Which is the I Tripoli standard maximum.
Right now, let's define the maximum password length.
And that is 64.
And that's also the, I believe, standard.
And next, we'll define.
The maximum connection retrace.
And I will use five tries.
And this pertains to the retried number.
On Disconnect.
So this will take care of our basic wildfire settings.
And just so you know where this definition comes from, this comes from the ISP, Wi-Fi types header
file.
And also, just so you're aware, these are the power safe mode options available.
Okay.
So here, let's create the network interface objects for the station and access point.
And we'll extend this so that it's visible everywhere.
And that's the ISP network interface structure as a pointer and call it ISP net if I stay.
And now we'll do the same for the access point.
And call it ESP that if AP.
Next we'll create the message IDs for the wi fi application task.
And I'll just make a note here for you that you can expand this.
Based on your application requirements.
And we'll actually expand this in the course and we'll say typedef enum.
And we can create a tag here for it.
It's really not necessary, but let's tag this as wi fi app message.
And say wi fi app message.
Start HTTP server.
And said, it's zero.
And we're going to send this photo SKU message where it will be received by a Wi-Fi application for
your autos test.
And when it's received, will handle starting the HTP server.
Okay, so we'll also have a wi fi app message.
Connecting from HTTP server.
And that's to let the wife by application know when we are connecting via the HTP server.
Okay.
And let's also create a wi fi app message.
Stay connected.
IP.
And we'll use this message to let the Wi-Fi application know when the ISP is connected to the external
access point or router and has been assigned an IP address.
Okay.
And let's call this wi fi app message.
Underscore E for Enam.
All right.
So we'll start with these messages for now.
And again, these messages will be handled by a Wi-Fi application for your Toast Task State machine
and will expand expanded as we progress in the course.
So now let's create.
A structure for the message.
Q.
And now we're really not doing much with this structure now other than sending the inner messages.
Well, I'll leave a note here for you as a reminder that you can expand it as you like.
So expand this based on your application requirements.
E.g. add another type and parameter as required.
So this will be a type to obstruct.
Why fight up Q message.
And we'll use our enum here.
WI fi app message enum.
And call it message ID.
All right.
Now, let's call it wi fi app.
Q message.
Underscore team.
Okay.
Good.
So now let's make our prototype.
Which sends a message to the Q.
Let's add a note about the parameter here.
And that's message it.
Which is the message idea from the wi fi message enum.
And the return will be true.
If an item was successfully sent to the queue.
Otherwise PD false.
And this is actually all caps you.
Okay.
And let's add a note here, because you may want to expand this on your own.
And I will say expand the parameter list.
Based on your requirements.
E.g. how you've expanded the wi fi app cube message structure.
Okay.
Good.
So for the function prototype, it'll return base type T.
And we'll call it wi fi app.
Send message.
And it'll take the wi fi app message enum.
And call it message ID.
Okay.
It looks good.
And the next prototype.
It starts the way.
Fine.
Auto task.
And let's say void wi fi app start.
And it takes no parameters.
All right.
So for the head of file, that should be all we need for now.
And it looks like there's a typo here, so let's fix that.
It should be 2552552550 for the net mask.
And.
Okay, great.
So I'll stop right here and we'll continue programming the wi fi application that C file for the next
one.
And be sure to check the resources for this lesson if you need further clarification on the topics covered.